Henry Kan Chen

Automation Engineer

Motivated automation engineer with 6+ years of experience working with customers to design, develop, and commissioning automation systems for industrial facilities. Experienced with self-driving vehicles, ROS framework, and tools like rviz and rqt. Proven communication skills. Passionate about robotics and wish to bring helpful robots for the world.

Work History

2017-09 -Current

Autonomous Vehicle Researcher (Master's Student)

University Of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

- Designed and developed an pedestrian communication system for the UW Moose, Canada's first self-driving car
- Integrated the system with the vehicle's ROS software and hardware system to produce a working prototype
- Measured and evaluated the prototype's performance with 4 custom-designed experiments
- Championed project schedule and coordinated participants for field tests

2012-10 -2018-12

Automation Engineer

TC Energy (formally TransCanada Pipelines), Calgary, AB

- Designed and developed 8+ automation and process control systems, using PLC and HMI, for natural gas transmission facilities
- Collaborated with multi-disciplinary teams and customers to implement and commission the new systems
- Collected system operational data in a process historian, extrapolated system performance, and performed root cause analysis on unscheduled shutdowns
- Actively engaged in continual improvement process to optimize engineering designs and project execution
- Trained plant operators on using the new system

Education

2017-09 -Current

Masters of Mathematics: Computer Science

University of Waterloo - Waterloo ON Cumulative GPA: 88.25 / Expected Completion: 2019/12

2001-09 -2006-06

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering

University of Calgary - Calgary AB Graduated with Distinction

Personal Info

Address

20 Wildwood Place Waterloo, ON, N2L 4B1

Phone

14036679095

E-mail

henry.chen.1@uwaterloo.ca

WWW

henrykanchen.github.io

Skills

C / C++ / Python



ROS / Linux



Communication and Teamwork



Customer Service



Attention to Detail



Languages

English



Mandrain / Cantonese

